A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, National Affairs, Office Files of Thomas Cooney FA653
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, National Affairs, Office Files of Thomas Cooney
1961-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA653
22.8 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Chronological Correspondence, 1974-1981; I
  - Correspondence, A-D, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, E-O, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, P-S, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, T-Z, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, A-J, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, K-R, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, A-R, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence Control Log, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence Control Log, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence Control Log, 1980 (Box 1)
- Budget and Fiscal Year Reports, 1967-1981; II
  - Social Development Granting Budgets (folder 1), 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Social Development Granting Budgets (folder 2), 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Social Development -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1969 (Box 1)
  - Social Development -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1970 (Box 1)
  - National Affairs -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1971 (Box 1)
  - Social Development -- Fiscal Year 1972 Planning Budget (folder 1), 1970-1972 (Box 1)
  - Social Development -- Fiscal Year 1972 Planning Budget (folder 2), 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Program Management Budget Submission and Budget Materials Fiscal Year 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Budget Planning Material Fiscal Year 1973, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Budget Fiscal Year 1973 and Later Drafts and Notes, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1974 (folder 1) (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1974 (folder 2) (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Planning Budgets Fiscal Year 1974-1975, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Planning Budget Fiscal Year 1975, 1974 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs -- Budget Fiscal Year 1975 (Box 2)
  - Management Costs and DAPs -- Fiscal Year 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs -- Social Development -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Management Budget Fiscal Year 1977 (Box 2)
  - Grant Actions for Inclusion in Fiscal Status Reports, May 14, 1977-Oct 30, 1978 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs -- Budget Reports Fiscal Year 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Status Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Social Development -- Planning Budget Fiscal Year 1981 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs/Social Development Budget (unfiled), 1967-1970 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs/Social Development Budget, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs/Social Development Budget, 1975-1979 (Box 2)
  - Budget, Fiscal Years 1975-1979, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
  - Alternative Budgets, 1976-1980 (Box 2)
- Program Reviews, 1978-1981; III
  - "National Affairs Current Programs: Background Comments and a Review", Nov 1, 1978 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs Program Review -- Session for Underclass Program, Jan 1981 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs Program Review -- Session 1: Overview, Jan 1981 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs Program Review -- Session 2: Communities and Neighborhoods, Jan 1981 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs Program Review -- Session 3: Civil Rights Program, Jan 1981 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs Program Review -- Session 4: Women's Program Review, Jan 1981 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs Program Review -- Session 5: Law and Justice Program, Jan 1981 (Box 2)
- The Underclass -- Health, Nutrition and Behavior, 1972-1981; IV
  - Baker, Sidney (Gesell Institute) (#795-0393), 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Barbados -- John, E. Roy/Ministry of Health of Barbados (LAC/SD) (#770-0471), 1977-1981 (Box 3)
  - Barbados Project -- Malnutrition and Behavior -- June 5, 1981 Meeting Materials (Box 3)
  - Barbados Project -- Ramsey/Galler/Solimano, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Beck, James C. -- Adolescent -- Learning Disability and Delinquency Studies; Ethical Review of Proposal, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Better Boys Foundation (#749-0823), 1975 (Box 3)
  - Bronx Nutrition Project -- Reports, Memoranda, etc., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Glidden -- Health, Nutrition, Behavior, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Calhoun/Levine (Delinquency Youth Studies) (#780-0243), 1976-1981 (Box 3)
  - Christakis, George -- Report, Memoranda Re: Nutrition and Adolescent Social Behavior, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Commonweal -- Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 3)
  - Commonweal -- RGAs, PRI, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Commonweal -- Proposals and Other Information, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Commonweal -- Michael Lerner (working file), 1978 (Box 3)
  - Consultants -- Mesnikoff, Alvin D.; Howard F. Andrews; Elmer L. Struening (DAP #749-0823), 1981 (Box 3)
  - Coursin, David Baird -- St. Joseph Hospital -- Cali, Colombia Meeting Re: Nutrition, Brain Development, and Behavior, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Deuschle, Kurt -- Mount Sinai Medical Center -- Correspondence Re: Harlem Community Organization to Improve Pregnancy Conditions, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Divoky, Diane -- Criticism of Ford Foundation Activities Re: Juvenile Health; Ford Foundation Response to Divoky, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Ethics in Experimentation and Research, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Ethics -- Memorandum and Article Re: Children as Research Subjects, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Ethics/Human Experimentation -- Memorandum, Feb 3, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation Early Childhood Programs, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation Policy Statement Re: Biomedical Research Involving Human Subjects, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Forms for Grants -- Blank Status Reports, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Allocations and Report Re: Biological Factors in Troublesome Juvenile Behavior (DAP #749-0823), 1974-1979 (Box 3)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior DAP #749-0823 -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports, Proposals, etc. (working file), 1974-1979 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior DAP #749-0823 -- Grants, DAPs, Budgets, General Correspondence (folder 1), 1974-1979 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior DAP #749-0823 -- Grants, DAPs, Budgets, General Correspondence (folder 2), 1974-1979 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior", 1976 (revised 1977) (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior" and Manuscript Corrections, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior" -- Inquiries Re: Paper (copies of replies enclosed), 1977 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior" -- Replies to Requests for Paper -- Public Departments, Hospitals, County/State, etc., 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior" -- Replies to Requests for Paper -- Schools, Colleges, Universities, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior" -- Replies to Requests for Paper -- Community Organizations, Groups, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior" -- Replies to Requests for Paper -- Individuals, Corporations, Banks, etc., 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Paper, "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors in Juvenile Anti-Social Behavior" -- Reactions and Comments on Paper, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Status Reports, 1976-1979 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Trip Reports, Meetings, Proposals, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Newspaper, Magazine Clippings, Miscellaneous Publications, Grant Actions and Ford Foundation "Letter", 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Extra Copies of Reports and Proposals, 1977-1980 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Program Interest In (reply form letters), 1976-1979 (Box 4)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior Meeting (April 9, 1976) -- Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior Meetings with OLAC Participants incl. Reports Re: Nutrition, Early Childhood Health, Rural Development, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior Meeting -- McGeorge Bundy's January 10, 1977 Meeting, Jan 10, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior Meeting (December 1977) (Box 5)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior DAP #749-0823 -- Updated Grant Information, Report, Grant List, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Updated Grants, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Ford Foundation Inter-Office -- Miscellaneous, 1977-1980 (Box 5)
  - Health, Nutrition, Behavior -- Miscellaneous (health exams), 1976 (Box 5)
  - Lachance, Paul -- Proposal, "Diet and Behavior" Re: Relationship of Hyperactivity to Food Additives, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Lerner, Michael (Growing Mind) [PHOTOS], 1976-1978 (Box 5)
  - Lerner, Michael -- Report, "Tomorrow's Children" Re: Nutritional and Environmental Stressors in Learning Disabilities, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Levine, Melvin -- Children's Hospital, Division of Youth Services, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Lewis, Dorothy O. -- Miscellaneous Papers Re: Juvenile Delinquency, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Margen, Sheldon -- University of California (#755-307), 1975-1978 (Box 5)
  - Meharry Medical College -- J.P. Carter Study -- Nutrition and Health on Anti-Social Behavior, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Mexican-American Unity Council (MAUC) -- Proposal and Study Re: Mexican-Americans in San Antonio, Texas, 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous -- Correspondence, Printed Material, etc. Re: Health, Nutrition, Human Nature, 1972-1979 (Box 5)
  - Murphy, Patrick -- Proposal Re: Juvenile Justice Seminar, 1976 (Box 5)
  - New York Institute for Child Development -- Hyperkinetic Children -- Proposals, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Norman K. Walker Associates, Inc. -- Correspondence Re: Learning Disabilities and SAT Scores, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Nutrition DAP (working file), 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - Pawel, Michael A., #805-0382 -- The August Aichhorn Residential Center for Adolescent Residential Care, Inc. (grant closed 9/30/1981), 1979-1981 (Box 5)
  - Pollitt's Proposal, "The Effects of Hunger on School Performance", 1975 (Box 6)
  - Pollitt, Ernesto -- "The U.S. School Feeding Program: Modes of Evaluating its Effects on the Behavior of Recipients", Nov 1976 (Box 6)
  - Pollitt, Ernesto -- Report Re: School Feeding Programs and Effects on Recipients' Behavior, 1977 (revised 1980) (Box 6)
  - Pollitt -- Reviews of Proposal, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Pollitt -- MIT/University of Texas -- Miscellaneous Papers Re: Fasting and Iron Deficiency on Cognitive Ability, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Program Interests in Health, Nutrition, Behavior and Juvenile Violence/Delinquency, Jan 1979 (Box 6)
  - Recommendation for Grant/DAP Actioin (RGA) Re: Disadvantaged Populations and Troublesome Behavior, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Reports Re: Nutrition and Mental Health, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - Report, "The Effects of Nutrition and Health on Anti-Social Behavior in Adolescence", 1975 (Box 6)
  - Report, "The Influence of Health on Adolescents' Social Adjustment and Educational Achievement in a Residential Treatment Center" by David Schwartz and Correspondence Re: Schwartz Consultancy and Proposal, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Report, "Public-Private Partnerships for Dealing with the Employment Problems of Youth", Sep 1977 (Box 6)
  - Report, "Biological Factors in Socially Troublesome Juvenile Behavior" by Thomas Cooney, Apr 18, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Report, "The Relationship between Children's Health and Intellectual Development" by Linda N. Edwards and Michael Grossman, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Report, "Impact of Nutrition on the Health of Americans", Jul 1981 (Box 6)
  - Report, "Public-Private Enterprise in Britain and America" by Charles Stainsby (folder 1) (Box 6)
  - Report, "Public-Private Enterprise in Britain and America" by Charles Stainsby (folder 2) (Box 6)
  - Review of Evaluation and Research on U.S. Government Domestic Nutrition Intervention Programs, Nov 1974 (Box 6)
  - Review of Ford Foundation Activities -- Health, Nutrition, Behavior as of July 31, 1977 (with amounts) (Box 6)
  - Review of Ford Foundation Activities -- Health, Nutrition, Behavior Among Juveniles as of July 31, 1977 (without amounts) (Box 6)
  - Review of Health, Nutrition, Behavior (without amounts), 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University -- Meeting and 1976-1977 Program Catalog (Box 6)
  - Schultz, Stephen R./Sheldon Margen -- HNB Consultant, 1978-1981 (Box 6)
  - South East Alabama Self-Help Association (SEASHA) and Nutrition Study, 1974-1977 (Box 7)
  - Spring, Bonnie -- Harvard University (#829- ), 1981 (Box 7)
  - Vera Institute of Justice (#805-0312) -- Haaga/Miller/Spofford (grant closed, 10/17/1980), 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Weingarten, Victor (consultant) -- incl. Report to Ford Foundation Re: Federal Programs in Nutrition, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Winick, Myron -- Columbia University (HNB) (#78-0911) (grant closed, 7/1/1981), 1978-1980 (Box 7)
  - Winick, Myron -- Columbia University (#805-0697) (grant closed, 9/24/1981), 1980-1981 (Box 7)
  - Wolff, Peter -- Children's Hospital -- Paper and Data Re: Study on Adolescent Delinquency, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Wolff, Peter and Richmond, Julius -- Judge Baker Guidance Center (#785-0289) (grant closed, 3/22/1979), 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Working Group on Nutrition -- DAP #809-0048 -- Policy Explorations in U.S. and Developing Countries on Nutrition and Health Paper by Sol Chafkin; Comments on Paper, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Working Group on Nutrition (Education and Public Policy) -- DAP #809-0048 -- incl. Report Re: Health, Nutrition and Population Activities in Thailand, 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Working Group on Nutrition -- DAP #809-0048 -- Neurological Endowment WGN Comments, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Working Group on Nutrition -- Sol Chafkin and Thomas Cooney to Look At Re: Health, Nutrition, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
  - Wurtman, Richard/Pollitt -- MIT (#770-0599) (grant closed, 10/20/1980), 1977-1978 (Box 7)
  - Wurtman/Fernstron -- MIT Miscellaneous Papers Re: Nutrition and the Brain, Memory Disorders, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
  - Wurtman, Richard -- MIT (HNB) (#78-0910) (grant closed, 5/30/1980), 1978-1980 (Box 7)
  - Wurtman, Richard -- MIT (#805-0186) (grant closed, 10/15/1981), 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Wurtman, Richard -- MIT (#805-0745), 1980 (Box 7)
  - Zimmerman, David -- Critique of "Health and Nutrition as Possible Factors...", 1977 (Box 7)
- Communities and Neighborhoods, 1969-1982; V
  - Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation -- A Comprehensive Development Plan, Nov 1978 (Box 8)
  - Belle Isle Cultural Center, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Columbia University Urban Center, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Assessment, 1971-1976 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Budget Fiscal Year 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- 5 Year Committments, 1969-1975, 1972-1977 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- CDC Commitments, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- New CDC Commitments, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Old CDC Commitments Material, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Paper -- Responses to April 5 CDC Paper, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Preliminary Report on Comprehensive Socio-Economic Community Development (Nashville, TN), Nov 21, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- RGAs -- DAP, South Bronx, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- RGAs -- SEASHA, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- RGAs -- Solomon Fuller Institute, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- RGAs -- NAACP Special Contribution Fund, Inc., 1980 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- RGAs -- University of Washington (Responsible Program Officer, William Pendleton), 1980 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- RGAs -- LISC -- Appropriation (Responsible Program Officer, Bernard McDonald), 1980 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Reports, Paper -- "New Instruments to Overcome Poverty", [1972] (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Reports, Paper -- CDC Information Paper and Related Memoranda, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Reports, Paper -- CDC Vignettes/Individual Association and Corporation Stories, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Reports, Paper -- CDC Paper -- Drafts, Background Material, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Reports, Paper -- CDC Paper (draft), Mar-Apr 1972 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Reports, Paper -- CDC Booklet, National Affairs Section of Annual Report, Sviridoff Essay Re: CDC's and Poor Communities, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Reports, Paper -- Promotion of CDC Paper, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Urban Institute Discussion Paper and Ford Foundation Information Paper, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Urban Institute Evaluation -- Ray Marshall Assessment of, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- Urban Institute Evaluation of Community Development Corporations, Mar 1976 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations -- K.S. Sweet Associates' Reports Re: CDCs, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Community Development Corporations, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Community Development Corporations, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Community Development Corporations -- "Some Observations on Ford Foundation Supported Community Development Corporations and Their Significance for Implementation of Government Policies and Programs" by Sol Chafkin, Oct 1977 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- Biennial and Annual Budgets (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- C&N Surveys, Blank Forms (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- CDC Expenditures, 1973-1977 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- Articles and Drafts Concerning C&N and Urban Affairs -- "Some Observations on Ford Foundation CDCs..." by Sol Chafkin, Oct 1977 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- Articles and Drafts Concerning C&N and Urban Affairs -- "Putting the "Community" Back into Community Revitalization" by Hugh Price, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- Articles and Drafts Concerning C&N and Urban Affairs -- "Community Board Participation in the New York City 1980 Budget" by Penn Kimball, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- Articles and Drafts Concerning C&N and Urban Affairs -- "Preliminary Notes on Grassroots Efforts in Contemporary America" by Janice Perlman, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- Articles and Drafts Concerning C&N and Urban Affairs -- C&N Organizations Information and Training Lists, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods -- Report, "Communities and Neighborhoods: A Possible Private Sector Initiative for the 1980s", Jan 2, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Communities and Neighborhoods, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Final Studies and Reports Under Service Agreements -- TA DAP (M. Hunter) Re: Community Development Corporations, Urban Development, Natural Resource Taxation, Land Management (folder 1), 1973-1979 (Box 9)
  - Final Studies and Reports Under Service Agreements -- TA DAP (M. Hunter) Re: Community Development Corporations, Urban Development, Natural Resource Taxation, Land Management (folder 2), 1977-1979 (Box 9)
  - Final Studies and Reports Under Service Agreements -- TA DAP (M. Hunter) -- "Report on the Woodlawn Organization's Financial Problems" (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation Conference on Community Development -- Summary Report, Jun 15-16, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Hamilton, Charles V. -- Ford Foundation Consultancy Re: Voting Behavior of Residents in Community Development Corporations, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Housing and Urban Development, Department of -- Community Development Corporations, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- DAP #809-0229 -- RGA (working file), 1980 (Box 9)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- DAP #809-0229 -- Discussion Paper Re: Communities and Neighborhoods; Appointments and Service Agreements; Organization Profiles, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Paper, "LISC: A Private-Public Venture", 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- Information Paper, "The Local Initiatives Support Corporation: National Support for Local Development", Mar 25, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- Fifth Avenue Committee (FAC), 1979 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- East New York Development Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- Flatbush Development Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- Grassroots Housing for a Better East New York, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- Renigades Housing Movement, Inc., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- 116th Street Block Association, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- La Raza en Accion Local, [1979] (Box 10)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- National Council of La Raza (Box 10)